[Music]
foreign
Advanced Training
so this is our lesson 11
in terms of advanced level Concepts
are it's a lesson 26 as an overall
treason testoster Concepts
so in this lesson 26
I'm gonna cover a very very important
concept called
enabling
self-healing mode are how can you
self-heal your test scripts when there
is a change in your locator properties
so this is a really very important
concept most of the organizations face
this challenge Whenever there is a new
build
for the application right all your
properties of your locators gets changed
so now how can you
overcome these kind of challenges by
using self-healing feature provided by
tricentistoska
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications before I publish more
videos
thank you
okay so what is this AI powered
self-healing in Tosca
so self-healing mode allows you to
execute your test cases without failing
even if a control in your system under
test has changed so that means Whenever
there is a change in the control
properties Whenever there is a new build
of your application
even though the properties of your
element is changed
the self-healing mode allows you to
execute your test cases without failing
them right and this ensures more stable
test runs reduces manual effort and
allows you to identify changed controls
and also this reduces the efforts for
automation scripts maintenance so
whenever there is a new build coming and
you lot of organization spends a lot of
money in modifying their scripts and
then re-exe give it in them so that
effort will be reduced and when you
create a module with Tosca xcan Tasker
automatically adds self-healing
properties to the self-healing property
tab of your module attribute
right that I am going to show you
shortly and also I'm gonna show you how
can you enable self-healing mode for
test cases
so two
enable self-healing mode for your
automated test cases in task Hall there
are four different steps first you need
to create a new test case with module
attribute that contains the self-healing
properties
and then you need to enable self-healing
mode for the test cases that you
automated and then you need to create an
execution list for the test cases and
run your execution list which does not
fail even though the properties of your
locator gets changed
so now I'm gonna show you practically
how this a powered self-healing
is going to work
seamlessly in presenters Tasker so it's
really really I never see this kind of
feature
in any other tools except catalog okay
so now now let's jump onto the system
and see how can we perform self-healing
by using present testoster latest
version
so this is my uh try sentence Tasker
latest version
2023 okay recently I have upgraded my
tricenters Tosca version 16. to 2023
okay so before I start uh explaining or
before I start automating one simple
test case and show you how can you
enable uh this Auto healing or
self-healing for any automated test case
right so before that let's go to their
official website
so this manual is actually its older
version but still this enabling
self-healing mode available for all the
versions 15 16 and 2023 as well okay so
here if you see it it has given entire
explanation how can you use uh the self
healing uh property or self-healing
um
feature interest Tasker
here okay in this page so you can go
through this page but anyway so
I'm going to explain the summary of this
page right by automating one test case
right so let's first automate one test
case so what is our test steps that we
need to perform so our first step is
create a new test case with module or
attribute that contains the self-healing
properties okay for that first let me
create one simple folder
called self healing okay let me right
click here and then create a folder
called self here okay now within this
folder I'm going to create one test case
right click
I'll make it as
itself healing the test case name is
selfie okay
so here first so as you all know a tri
sentence has their own demo webshop
e-commerce website okay where you can
practice all your
test cases or you can automate different
scenarios by using sample website okay
so this is what I'm gonna use okay so
for that first we need to capture the
modules right so let's go to trecent
Stars car and go to modules I'm going to
explain from the scratch okay
so right click and then create
oh sorry instead of creating a module I
want to just simply right click and scan
the application
okay so it displays a window where you
can select the application that you
would like to scan okay
so it is starting your xcan
and it gives you to select the
application so this is the application
that I would like to scan okay right
click and scan
first I would like to scan my top menu
okay what up menu I want to scan all the
objects related to top menu right
register login shopping cart wishlist so
I already published enormous number of
um YouTube videos explaining all these
Concepts so you can just visit my
description where I've pasted the
playlist of my tricent testoster 16 the
playlist of treason testoster sap write
all these links in the description okay
so now if you see these are the top menu
links so I would like to add register
also and then login
and then shopping cart
and wishlist okay and then I would like
to rename this as
top
menu okay so now let's simply
save this okay let me save it
done
so objects are saved and closed so now
let's go back to your present testoster
so this is the one that we added just
now right demo webshop
let me scroll down here so this one demo
webshop
top menu so this one we added register
login are done now I would like to
automate login feature so for that I'm
going to click on login now I would like
to capture all these objects related to
login
for that what we'll do I'm gonna again
come back here
and then right click here and scan
application
so before I scan application as we are
doing
um Auto healing right capability I want
to make a small change in the
application okay let me do that okay
let's close this I don't want to scan
um
anything here here I want to inspect
this login button and what I'll do I'm
gonna change the name of this logging
button okay so let me do that okay let's
change the name of this login button to
sign in
okay
so if you see here now I changed the
name
of this button from login to sign in
right now I will scan the module okay
right click and then scan the
application
so this is my initial version of
application so in the initial version of
application the developers deployed
that application has the button called
sign in as you've got okay so now I am
scanning entire application right I'm
scanning the application where I would
like to capture these login password
sign in button remember me right so if
you see here I have password this is my
password edit box
so if you want I can simply
highlight this see this is my password
and this is my email correct it is ideal
highlighting right side
and then this is my sign in see sign in
point button is recognizing now okay and
then forgot password link
right that's it and then remember me
check box
this is my checkbox okay so it's
highlighted now right so done so now I
would like to
save this application okay let's save
this module
okay save it
and what is the name of this so this is
demo webshop let me rename this as again
pipe symbol login okay save this
so now let's close this okay
so this is done
so now what I will do okay let's again
go back to our task if
you are the new modules that we added
correct
now let's say Hey you automated your
let's automate the test Case by using
these modules new models right let's
automate our test cases login test case
what we'll do I'm gonna just drag this
module and
let me put it right side okay so that I
can simply drag and drop my modules okay
here first I would like to open the URL
right for this
Ctrl t
and then type open URL
okay these are all very basic concepts
okay I already explained in my previous
class videos okay simply copy this
and what is the URL This is My URL so
once you
enter your url
I did not copy entire thing okay let's
copy this
copy
and paste it here done so now once I
open the URL next step is clicking on
this login so we already captured that
those modules right drag this and simply
drop here
done so what I need to do I need to
click on login link so that's why I'm
gonna enter value as X so which clicks
the login button login link right done
now next Once here I hit login
I need to enter username password so
here this is my login page module right
just drag and drop here
and here I would like to enter the
values of my email
and then the password
and here I'm gonna click on sign in
button
okay done
so now let's save this
so now let's see if you see here let me
re see if you see I refreshed this
website let's say developer
made some changes to this website
if you go to login
now the login button is
instead of signing when we scanned that
button is actually signing but now it is
login
if I execute this this test okay yes
what happens it's gonna fail right let's
run this test case now let's close this
and let me run this test case right
click and run and see what happens okay
so generally it fails right the test
case will fail
so what if let's see now okay so if the
test cases are getting failed Whenever
there is a new build because of the
property changes
then you have to again go to your
corresponding modules see it is running
entered now in login it's not going to
find out that login
so every time the property changes then
you need to update your modules and the
properties locators right so instead of
that
can handle these scenarios
because
the property got changed it can simply
Auto heal by using some or other
properties of this button it can Auto
heal by itself or it can self heal by
itself how can we do that so let's go
back here okay so it simply says it it
could not find the button right it it is
not able to find the button right so now
how can we Auto heal this to Auto heal
so let's go back here what is our next
step enable
self-healing mode so in before that
create new test case with module
attribute that contains the self-healing
properties now I need to add some
self-healing properties while scanning
my login module right when I was
scanning the login module that time I
have to capture some self healing
properties so let me show you again that
okay let's rescan this okay I want to
rescan this module again so because I am
doing the second time
rescanning why earlier we haven't added
any self-healing properties so generally
whenever I scan for the first time
itself you can add your self-healing
properties as well so which saves lot of
your time okay so let me just go back
here again
I'm just making the same change like I'm
just changing the button name back to
sign in so that it can identify your
object okay see generally what you'll do
right click
rescan so when you are scanning your
modules you need to make sure that you
also scan yourself healing properties
so generally Tyson test task are
captures all the self healing properties
let me show you what are these
self-healing properties that
tries and testoster captures by default
okay Tyson testoster captures by default
okay so let me show the what are those
okay if you see here
earlier
captured sign in right button so when
you capture the sign in button let's go
back here so this is my sign in button
correct and what are the properties that
it took to identify the properties so
these are the identify identifier
properties identify by properties it is
taking tag and value sign in tag input
right these two are the properties it
captured but now because the button name
is changed it is not able to identify so
if you see on top here you can see
self-healing properties click on this
self-healing properties of your sign in
button is these are the self-healing
properties
what label signing
class Name ID I don't want to use this
because this is blank name I don't want
to use this this is black I'm making
some changes I want to use Tag I don't
want to use title let's say value
let's give valuable so that's not a
problem okay or because you already
added value property in the main
property right so I don't want to use
this value property okay
so what I am taking I am taking
I want to add XPath Also let's keep
value also that's not a problem
self-healing properties okay all these
properties apart from value I'm adding
XPath I'm adding tag uh I want to add
type right I want to add class name
and then label let's remove label right
I want to add also action point also
okay action point also I want to add
okay let's add all these
and now save this okay so you understand
right where you can see self healing
properties right if we again click on
this it's going to show you normal
properties that object is getting
identified okay
default properties save this now okay so
that is done let's close this so as I
told you okay now because the
application is got enhanced and your
button is changed to login right so now
when you are running the script it is
not able to
self heal okay
now while scanning your module we also
added self-healing properties now what
is our next step is our next step is
enable self healing mode for the test
case how can you enable self healing
mode okay the self-healing mode Let's go
back here let me quickly
show you try sentence Tasker
self-healing okay if you see here when
you are enabling self-healing more
there are three different types of
enablements right there are three
different types okay let me just go here
self-healing
it's opening self-healing website okay
yeah if you see here
when you are enabling self-healing
so there are three different types of
options that you can select one is
weighted option assigns of 18 waiting
algorithm to self-healing properties to
find the most unique control
okay
and the next one is combination creates
all possible combinations of all
properties that are stored in steering
param self-healing data
to find the suitable control
false that means it disables your
self-healing mode okay let's go back to
our Tri sentence Tasker so before I
enable self mode self-healing mode for
the test case I'll just want to show you
whatever the self-healing properties
that we captured here right let's go
about to here okay if you see after
besides your detailed tab you have
another tab called self-healing
properties
so whatever self-healing properties that
we captured these are the self-healing
properties
tag you have a weightage of 0.25
and then class name you have a weightage
of one XPath you have weightage of one
value you have weightage of one type 0.5
action point one so you have a
self-healing properties and trisantis
task are by using Auto filter artificial
intelligence it captured all these
self-healing properties and it is
providing weightage to those properties
okay so that it helps in self healing
even though your properties got changed
for the particular object okay so now
let's go back to your test case whatever
we automated right
now I want to enable self-healing here
here you can see still the button login
button is now signing right that will
not work in the new build because your
button is changing now so now let me
enable self healing okay here I want to
First add browser property first
I want to execute this test case on edge
browser okay and then
here I want to add another
test configuration parameter called self
healing
healing okay and I want to choose a
combination property I can select
weighted or combination right first I
want to select combination property here
okay I selected combination property
okay and now let's save this here I
saved it now let's close the application
now let me run this again now okay let
me run the test case now
now this time Tasker should enable your
self-healing property okay right click
and run this
so it enables self-healing property and
it uses the properties that we saved in
the self-healing properties okay so it
opened it clicked on login it simply
enters email and password now it starts
thinking login
now your login button is changed
what it will do it self heals and it
should not fail see it did not fail it
clicked on login
perfect that means our self-healing is
working so let's go back to
see the magic now okay see the magic
this is our magic but now again let me
tell you one more thing let's use let's
see our test results
if you see here
there is a symbol right self-healing
symbol right with a love symbol and your
heart rate right that means this
particular sign in button it could not
identify but it applied self healing
right if you expand this it clearly says
here it says self-healing combination
certainty seven combinations
and it identified a unique control
called class name but earlier what was
the control
let me see here let's go back to again
let's go back here go back to our module
okay let me just put this aside okay let
me put this
here
let's put this here PSI by sideways okay
let's put sideways let's close this now
and here if you see if you go to modules
the sign in property what is what does
it has the sign-in property is having
actually the sign in property is being
identified sign in button is being
identified by value called sign in but
now the value is changed to login
correct but if you see here in the
self-healing results it says the unique
property what it identified the unique
property called class name instead of
value it took the class name correct so
this is the class name
it identified the button by using the
property called class name now see the
magic okay see the magic let me just
bring this back again
to main here okay see the magic here now
okay what I'll do here now oh let it let
me put this aside only okay what I'll do
I want to know because the property got
changed now I want to apply this new
property I want to apply this new
property so if you see here right click
here now right click here now apply self
healing properties because no property
got changed I want to apply this new
property simply hit apply healing
property if You observe here see now
old property our old locator got
replaced with the new locator
you understand right and simply save
this
that means
if any element locator properties
changed while running in the application
it auto heals and then you can update
your properties with the latest
properties you can update your modules
with the latest properties so that means
Whenever there is a new build it's a
very very genuine or very very common
occurring problem in automation is
script maintenance
Whenever there is a new build the tester
says all the properties got changed now
my application is breaking my automation
scripts are breaking so now you need not
to worry about it
will Auto Hill
your test scripts and all the test
results will be passed and it updates
your
properties with the latest locators
so that's the advantages that's the
beauty of your self-healing property of
your tricentistoscope hope you all
understand the very very important
concept of self-healing enabling
self-healing in the trisentis task test
scripts if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your queries thank you
[Music]